Guide to the William Heyen Papers YCAL MSS 352
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- January 2010 Acquisition, 1961-2009; 322142; (13 boxes)
  - Writings, 2005-2009; 322161
    - Annotated Books, 322162
      - McKibben, Bill. Hope, Human and Wild, 322200 (Box 39)
        Contains the first draft (p.7) of a yet unpublished poem, and the first draft of the poem that became "Subway" and appears in The Rope (2003).
      - McPhee, John. Rising from the Plains, 322199 (Box 39)
        This book contains the first drafts of two poems that appeared in Crazy Horse in Stillness (1996) and a 3 x 5 card laid in with a draft of another poem.
      - Melchior, Ib and Brandenburg, Frank. Quest: Searching for Germany's Nazi Past., 322198 (Box 39)
        This book contains the first drafts of "Swans" and "Bloodhound" which appear in Shoah Train.
      - Messegue, Maurice. Of Men and Plants, 322197 (Box 39)
        This book contains the first draft of section XLVIII of Noise in the Trees (1974).
      - Mitchell, John Hanson. Living at the End of Time., 322196 (Box 39)
        This book contains the first draft of the poem that became "Walden" which appears in The Rope (2003).
      - Nero, Robert W. Redwings, 322195 (Box 39)
        This book contains the 1st draft of "Epaulettes" which appeared in Crazy Horse in Stillness.
      - Newcomb, Richard F. Iwo Jima, 322194 (Box 39)
        This book contains the first drafts of many stanzas of "Iwo Dahlia," a poem appearing in A Poetics of Hiroshima & Other Poems.
      - Niewyk, Donald L. Fresh Wounds: Early Narratives of Holocaust Survival, 322193 (Box 39)
        This book contains the first drafts of several poems appearing in Shoah Train.
      - Noel, Daniel. Seeing Castaneda, 322192 (Box 39)
        This book contains, among drafts of other poems, the first draft of "Castaneda," which appears in Pig Notes & Dumb Music (1998).
      - Norton, M.D. Herter. Translations from the Poetry of Rainer Maria Rilke, 322191 (Box 39)
        This book contains the first draft of "Lament" that appears in Erika: Poems of the Holocaust.
      - Nyiszli, Miklos. Auschwitz: A Doctor's Eyewitness Account, 322190 (Box 40)
        This book contains early drafts of several poems that appear in Shoah Train, including "Bread," "Auschwitz Reich Disfigured Haiku Sequence," "Luftpost," "The Pines," "Stones: the Efficacy of Poetry," "Ardor," and "Had."
      - Poller, Walter. Medical Block Buchenwald, 322189 (Box 40)
        This book contains the first drafts of the poem that became "Communion Spoon" to be included in Shoah Train.
      - Rabinowitz, Dorothy. New Lives: Survivors of the Holocaust Living in America, 322188 (Box 40)
        This book contains the first draft of "The Hair: Jacob Korman's Story" which appeared in Erika.
      - Rees, Laurence. Auschwitz: A New History, 322187 (Box 40)
        This book contains first drafts of "The Word," "The Carriages," "Exercise," "The Poet Laureate Speaks," "Poetry."
      - Rosenberg, David. Ed. Testimony: Contemporary Writers Make the Holocaust Personal., 322186 (Box 40)
        This book contains the first drafts of the poem that became "The Others," which appears in Shoah Train.
      - Sakutaro, Hagiwara. Face at the Bottom of the World, 322185 (Box 40)
        This book contains drafts of the unpublished poem "Slug."
      - Sandoz, Mari. The Buffalo Hunters, 322184 (Box 40)
        This book contains the first drafts of several poems that appeared in Crazy Horse in Stillness (1996). "Aerial View, BC," "Ice," "Providence," "Friendlies," and "Libido Saloon."
      - Schloegl, Irmgard. The Wisdom of the Zen Masters, 322183 (Box 40)
        The back flyleaf contains the 1st draft of a prose piece that appears in Pig Notes & Dumb Music: Prose on Poetry.
      - Schumach, Murray. The Diamond People, 322182 (Box 40)
        This book contains the first drafts of a couple pieces in Pig Notes & Dumb Music: Prose on Poetry (1998).
      - Selzer, Richard. Mortal Lessons: Notes on the Art of Surgery, 322181 (Box 40)
        First drafts of "The Dome" are written on back flyleaves. "The Dome" appears in The Confessions of Doc Williams & Other Poems (2006).
      - Shapard, Robert and James Thomas. Sudden Fiction: American Short-Short Stories, 322180 (Box 40)
        First drafts of "The Village," "Son" and "Grist" are in this book. These stories appear in The Hummingbird Corporation: Stories (2003).
      - Sipper, Ralph. Modern First Editions, Cat. 54., 322179 (Box 40)
        The last page here contains the first draft of my "Old Flame" that appears in The Hummingbird Corporation: Stories (2003).
      - Stafford, Kim. Early Morning: Remembering My Father, 322178 (Box 40)
        This book contains poem fragments and an inlaid draft of a poem titled "Beginning with a line from William Stafford."
      - Steinberg, Paul. Speak You Also: A Survivor's Reckoning, 322177 (Box 40)
        This book contains drafts of a couple poems including "Cabbage Steam."
      - Stevens, John. One Robe, One Bowl: The Zen Poetry of Ryokan., 322176 (Box 40)
        Note by Heyen reads: "The poem on the back fly leaf became a Tamarack postcard." The book also contains inlaid notes.
      - Stryk, Lucien. Encounter with Zen, 322175 (Box 40)
        Contains drafts of a poem on the back flyleaf. This book is inscribed by Stryk for Han and Bill Heyen on the title page
      - Suzuki, Daisetz Teitaro. The Training of the Zen Buddhist Monk, 322174 (Box 40)
        Poem fragments are scattered throughout.
      - Tall, Deborah. From Where We Stand: Recovering a Sense of Place, 322173 (Box 40)
        Page 241 and the back flyleaf contain the beginnings of poems that, as Heyen notes, became poems from Crazy Horse in Stillness.
      - Tanahashi, Kazuaki. Essential Zen, 322172 (Box 40)
        This book contains drafts of unpublished poems and some notes on a pig note about the moon in the river that appeared in Pig Notes & Dumb Music.
      - Teale, Edwin Way. A Naturalist Buys an Old Farm, 322171 (Box 41)
        Laid in are the drafts of what never became a section of The Chestnut Rain, about a chestnut sill Teale mentions.
      - Trevelyan, George and Belle Valerie Gaunt. A Tent in Which to Pass a Summer Night, 322170 (Box 41)
        This book contains the first drafts of "Easter Morning," which appeared in Shoah Train: Poems, and of the pig note that concludes Pig Notes & Dumb Music.
      - Van Der Post, Laurens. The Voice of the Thunder, 322169 (Box 41)
        This book contains two unpublished poem drafts.
      - Wagner, Gottfried. Twilight of the Wagners: The Unveiling of a Family's Legacy, 322168 (Box 41)
        This book contains the first drafts of the poems "Zeitpost," "Kindred Spirits," and "The Key" which will appear in Shoah Train.
      - Wiesenthal, Simon. The Sunflower, 322167 (Box 41)
        Heyen's responses are written on pages 99-100 and 208.
      - Williamson, Chilton. Roughnecking It, 322166 (Box 41)
        This book contains the first drafts of 2-3 poems that appeared in Crazy Horse in Stillness (1996).
      - Worth, C. Brooke. Of Mosquitoes, Moths, and Mice, 322165 (Box 41)
        This book contains the first drafts of the poem "Egg."
      - Zassenhaus, Hiltgunt. Walls: Resisting the Third Reich—One Woman's Story, 322164 (Box 41)
        An unpublished poem is written on the back flyleaf.
      - Zweig, Paul. Walt Whitman: the Making of the Poet, 322163 (Box 41)
        This book's back flyleaves contain the first drafts of an unpublished poem Heyen spent many years revising: "The Fountain Pen: An Autobiography."
  - Journals (bound and published copies), 1965-2008; 322152
    Included are bound copies of original journals held by the Rare Books and Special Collections, University of Rochester and which have been published as The Cabin: Journal 1964-1985, copies of which are also included.
    - Journal no. 1, 1965-1974; 322160 (Box 42)
    - Journal no. 2, 1975-1980; 322159 (Box 42)
    - Journal no. 3, 1980-1981; 322158 (Box 42)
    - Journal no. 4, 1982-1983; 322157 (Box 42)
    - Journal no. 5, 1983-1984; 322156 (Box 42)
    - Journal no. 6, 1984-1985; 322155 (Box 42)
    - Journal no. 7, 1985 Jan-Jun; 322154 (Box 42)
    - The Cabin: Journal 1964-1985, 2 copies, 2008; 322153; 2 Folders (Box 42)
  - Collaboration with Robert E. Marx, 2003-2008; 322145
    Includes material relating to a planned limited-edition book, A Poetics of Hiroshima: Two Poems by William Heyen & 12 Etchings by Robert Marx, to have been printed by Terence Chouniard at Wells College and under the imprint of The Black Bird Press, Marx's press with which he published collaborations with Daniel Berrigan, Elizabeth Bishop, Milton Kessler, and other poets. Material includes correspondence, manuscripts, proofs, and 17 etchings signed by Marx.
    - Marx Project, circa 2007-2008; 322151 (Box 43)
    - Printed material, "Considering the Voluntary Absence of God", 2003; 322150 (Box 43)
    - Correspondence, 2006-2008; 322149; 3 Folders (Box 43)
    - A Poetics of Hiroshima with Marx etchings, circa 2007-2008; 322148 (Box 43)
    - A Poetics of Hiroshima, 2008; 322147 (Box 43)
    - Etchings signed by Robert Marx, 322146 (Box 44)
  - Oversize, 322143
    - SUNY Brockport basketball photo (from Correspondence), 1961; 322144 (Box 44)
- March 2011 Acquisition, 1979–2010; 0.21 Linear Feet (1 box)
  This portion of the collection features correspondence between William Heyen and Michael Broomfield.
  Arranged alphabetically by file title.
  - Computer files
    - Email correspondence with Michael Broomfield, 1981–2010
  - Correspondence, Broomfield, Michael, 1979–1990 (Box 46)
- October 2015 Acquisition, 1915–2015; 27.22 Linear Feet (31 boxes)
  This portion of the collection consists of correspondence, writings of William Heyen and other authors, artwork, annotated books containing early drafts of Heyen's poems, and personal, financial and legal papers, as well as audiovisual and computer media documenting Heyen's career.
  Organized into six subseries: Correspondence, Writings, Artwork, Annotated Books, Personal and Financial Papers, and Audiovisual and Computer Media.
  - Correspondence
    This subseries consists of correspondence of Heyen with his friends and colleagues, including Louis Daniel Brodsky, Craig Cotter, John Felstiner, Douglas Knehans, DeLoss McGraw, Joyce Carol Oates, and Cynthia Ozick, and correspondence with immediate and extended family, including Heyen's wife, Hannelore Heyen.
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent or file title, with unidentified correspondence filed at the end of the sequence.
    - "A" general, 1988–2014 (Box 47)
    - Abrams, Sam, 2010–2013 (Box 47)
    - Allman, John, 1996–2013 (Box 47)
    - Arthur, Robert, 2012–2013 (Box 47)
    - Axelrod, David, 2006–2012 (Box 47)
    - "B" general, 2002–2014 (Box 47)
    - Baggett, Rebecca, 2010–2011 (Box 47)
    - Bellagio, 1991–1997 (Box 47)
    - Bentley, Roy, 2010–2013 (Box 47)
    - Bizzaro, Patrick, 2007–2013 (Box 47)
    - Bluestone, Stephen, 2009–2014 (Box 47)
    - Bonczek, Michelle, 2011–2014 (Box 47)
    - Bowling, Tim, 2010–2013 (Box 47)
    - Brady, Philip, 2007–2013 (Box 47)
    - Brennessel, Barry, 2012–2014 (Box 47)
    - Brodsky, Louis Daniel, 2009 (Box 47)
    - Broomfield, Michael, 2010–2014 (Box 47)
    - Byrnes, Fred, 2009–2012 (Box 47)
    - "C" general, 1996–2014 (Box 47)
    - Chautauqua, 2004–2013 (Box 47)
    - Cipullo, Tom, 1999–2011 (Box 47)
    - Claeson, Stewe, 2011–2013 (Box 47)
    - Clementa, Vince, 2010–2011 (Box 47)
    - Cologne-Brookes, Gavin, 2002–2013 (Box 47)
    - Conlon, Christopher, 2009–2012 (Box 47)
    - Coray, Anne, 2010–2013 (Box 47)
    - Cotter, Craig, 2005–2014 (Box 47)
    - Cotter, Craig, 2005–2014; 8 Folders (Box 48)
    - "D" general, 2009–2014 (Box 48)
    - Davis, Todd, 2009–2014 (Box 48)
    - Deming, Richard, 2012–2013 (Box 48)
    - Duva, Gregory, 2008–2011; 3 Folders (Box 48)
    - DiMatteo, Rosemarie, 2010–2011 (Box 48)
    - Drury, John, 2011 (Box 48)
    - Dzwonkoski, Peter, 2012–2015 (Box 48)
    - "E" general, 2001–2011 (Box 48)
    - Ehrlich, Robert, 2009–2013 (Box 48)
    - Eradam, Yusuf, 2003 (Box 48)
    - Esposito, Duane and Lisa, 2006–2013 (Box 48)
    - "F" general, 2003–2014 (Box 48)
    - Felstiner, John, 2003–2010 (Box 48)
    - Fitzpatrick, Richard, 2009–2011 (Box 48)
    - Fulbright, 1971–1972 (Box 48)
    - "G" general, 1989–2013 (Box 48)
    - Gaffney, Larry, 2007–2013 (Box 48)
    - Gale Research Inc., 1987–1989 (Box 48)
    - Gibbons, Robert, 2010–2014; 3 Folders (Box 48)
    - Goodman Associates, 1981–1997 (Box 49)
    - Gore, Patricia, 2009–2013 (Box 49)
    - Gronlund, Geoff, 2012–2014 (Box 49)
    - "H" general, 2000–2014 (Box 49)
    - Haven, Stephen, 2009–2012 (Box 49)
    - Hawaii, 1983–1985 (Box 49)
    - Heyen, correspondence, 2013 (Box 50)
    - Heyen family, 2008–2014 (Box 51)
    - Heyen, Hannelore, 2002–2013 (Box 51)
    - Hix, H. L. (Harvey Lee), 2010–2012 (Box 51)
    - Holcomb, Grant, 2009–2013 (Box 51)
    - Holmes, Tom, 2011–2014 (Box 51)
    - Inger, Earl, 2012–2013 (Box 51)
    - "J" general, 1989–2013 (Box 51)
    - "K" general, 1989–2013 (Box 51)
    - Katz, Eliot, 2006–2014 (Box 51)
    - Kelbaugh, Ken, 2007–2013 (Box 51)
    - Knehans, Douglas, 2005–2010; 3 Folders (Box 51)
    - Krampf, Thomas, 2010–2013 (Box 51)
    - Krapf, Norbert, 2010–2013; 2 Folders (Box 51)
    - "L" general, 1996–2013 (Box 51)
    - Ladin, Jay, 2005–2006; 2 Folders (Box 51)
    - Leopard, Susan, 2011–2015 (Box 51)
    - "M" general, 1983–2013 (Box 51)
    - Masterson, Dan, 2000–2010 (Box 51)
    - Matthews, Jack, 2009–2014 (Box 51)
    - Mazzaro, Jerome, 2008–2014 (Box 51)
    - McGraw, DeLoss, 1993–2015; 3 Folders (Box 51)
    - Mees, William J., 2002–2012 (Box 52)
    - Merrifield, Karla Linn, 2004–2013 (Box 52)
    - Merten, Imke and Werner, 2000–2013 (Box 52)
    - Moscaliuc, Mihaela, 2011–2012 (Box 52)
    - Murphy, Peter E., 1986–1998 (Box 52)
    - "N" general, 2007–2013 (Box 52)
    - Nicastro, Kathleen, 2007–2013; 3 Folders (Box 52)
    - "O" general, 2010–2013 (Box 52)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1976–1995 (Box 52)
    - Ozick, Cynthia, 2007–2010 (Box 52)
    - "P" general, 2008–2013 (Box 52)
    - Philips, Robert, 2009–2013 (Box 52)
    - Prager, June, 1995–2013 (Box 52)
    - Pritts, Nate, 2009–2014 (Box 52)
    - Pterodactyl Rose, 1993 (Box 52)
    - Pulitzer Prize, 1991 (Box 52)
    - "R" general, 2009–2013 (Box 52)
    - Ray, David, 2002–2013 (Box 52)
    - Roberson, William, 1987–2006 (Box 52)
    - Roche, John, 2010–2014 (Box 52)
    - Ruggieri, Helen, 2010–2014 (Box 52)
    - "S" general, 1929–2014 (Box 52)
    - Sinesiou, Adam, 2012–2014 (Box 52)
    - Smith, Joyce, 2009–2014 (Box 52)
    - Spires, Elizabeth, 2000–2012 (Box 52)
    - Stryk, Dan, 2010–2012 (Box 52)
    - "T" general, 2008–2013 (Box 52)
    - Tillet, Robert, 2011–2012 (Box 52)
    - Trzaska, Kenneth, 2010–2013 (Box 52)
    - "U-V" general, 2009–2013 (Box 52)
    - Vallone, Antonio, 2000–2014 (Box 52)
    - VandeZande, Jeffrey, 2011–2014 (Box 52)
    - "W" general, 1987–2014 (Box 52)
    - Waters, Michael, 2009–2014 (Box 52)
    - Weyermann, Trudi, 2001 (Box 52)
    - Whitehead, Jett, 2009–2013 (Box 52)
    - Wolpe, Sholeh, 2009–2013 (Box 52)
    - "Z" general, 1996 (Box 52)
    - Zausin, Michael, 2004–2008 (Box 52)
    - Zimmer, Paul, 2009–2014 (Box 52)
    - Unidentified, 2010–2014 (Box 52)
  - Writings
    This subseries consists of drafts of Heyen's poetry and prose, as well as contributions from others on collaborative projects, such as drafts of musical scores by Douglas Knehans.
    - The Angel Voices
      - Complete draft with annotations, 2010 (Box 53)
      - Draft with annotations, 2010 (Box 53)
      - Galleys, correspondence, 2010 (Box 53)
      - Galleys, correspondence, editorial suggestions, 2010 (Box 53)
    - Anthology Preface, undated (Box 53)
    - Bellows, George, annotations, undated (Box 53)
    - The Candle
      - Draft with annotations, 2013 (Box 53)
      - Drafts, notes, 2013–2014 (Box 53)
      - Galley with annotations, 2013 (Box 53)
    - Clippings, 1961–2009 (Box 53)
    - Crazy Horse and The Custers
      - Complete draft with annotations, 2013 (Box 53)
      - Draft with annotations, 2013 (Box 53)
      - "Part Two" draft with annotations, correspondence, 2013 (Box 53)
      - Poetry drafts with annotations, 2013 (Box 53)
    - "Death of Field", 1970 (Box 53)
    - Distant Survivors
      - Complete draft with annotations, 2006 (Box 53)
      - Drafts with annotations, correspondence, 2006 (Box 53)
      - Drafts with annotations, correspondence, 2011 (Box 53)
    - Ephemera, 1974–2011; 2 Folders (Box 53)
    - "Erika", 1984 (Box 54)
    - "Falling From Heaven", 1991 (Box 54)
    - Football Corporations
      - Complete draft with annotations, 2010; 2 Folders (Box 54)
      - Draft, printout, corrections, 2009 (Box 54)
    - "Funnel", undated (Box 54)
    - Heyen, LOC catalog, 2000 (Box 54)
    - Hiroshima Suite
      - Complete draft with annotations, 2012 (Box 54)
      - Draft, 2010 (Box 54)
      - Drafts with annotations, 2012 (Box 54)
    - "Homage to a Mentor", 2011 (Box 54)
    - Journals (bound and published copies)
      - Journal no. 8, 1985 June 30–1986 May 13 (Box 55)
      - Journal no. 9, 1986 May 14–October 5 (Box 55)
      - Journal no. 10, 1986 October 6–1987 July 9 (Box 55)
      - Journal no. 11, 1987 July 12–1988 July 1 (Box 55)
      - Journal no. 12, 1988 July 2–1989 August 6 (Box 55)
      - Journal no. 14, 1989 August 7–1990 July 24 (Box 56)
      - Journal no. 16, 1991 June 10–September 2 (Box 56)
      - Journal no. 17, 1991 September 4–1992 February 9 (Box 56)
      - Journal no. 18, 1992 February 10–May 8 (Box 56)
      - Journal no. 19, 1992 May 14–August 21 (Box 56)
      - Journal no. 20, 1992 August 22–December 18 (Box 57)
      - Journal no. 21, 1992 December 21–1993 May 6 (Box 57)
      - Journal no. 22, 1993 May 11–November 18 (Box 57)
      - Journal no. 23, 1993 November 20–1994 June 2 (Box 57)
      - Journal no. 24, 1994 June 4–October 25 (Box 57)
    - Little Mag project, undated (Box 54)
    - My Life with Joyce Carol Oates
      - Draft with annotations, undated (Box 54)
      - Drafts, undated (Box 54)
      - Drafts, notes, annotations, undated (Box 54)
      - Galleys with annotations, 2000 (Box 54)
      - Notes, undated (Box 54)
      - Novelist draft, undated (Box 54)
      - Novelist draft, correspondence, 2011 (Box 54)
      - Novelist drafts, annotations, correspondence, 2000 (Box 54)
    - "Oil Psyche", 2010 (Box 54)
    - Poems published online, printouts, 2000–2014 (Box 54)
    - Poetry drafts, 2005–2011; 2 Folders (Box 54)
    - Poetry drafts, 2006 (Box 54)
    - Poetry drafts, 2009–2010 (Box 58)
    - Poetry drafts, 2010–2012 (Box 58)
    - Poetry drafts, 2011–2012 (Box 58)
    - Poetry drafts, notes, 2000 (Box 58)
    - Red Heifer sequence/project, 2010 (Box 58)
    - Self-interview project, undated (Box 58)
    - Score for Shoah Requiem by Douglas Knehans, 2005; 4 Folders (Box 59)
    - "Shoah Train", 2003 (Box 60)
    - Straight's Suite
      - Draft with annotations, 2009 (Box 61)
      - Drafts with annotations, notes, 2010–2011 (Box 61)
      - Drafts with annotations, notes, 2011–2012 (Box 61)
      - Straight Suite for Frank O'Hara [drafts], 2008–2009 (Box 61)
    - Studies Memorial Service, 2009 (Box 61)
    - "Swastika Poems", 1977 (Box 61)
    - Terman interview, 2009 (Box 61)
    - "To My Sister", 2014 (Box 61)
    - "To William Merwin", 2007 (Box 61)
    - Vic Holyfield and the Class of 1957
      - Drafts with annotations, correspondence, 2012 (Box 61)
      - Draft with annotations, notes, 2011 (Box 61)
      - Draft with annotations, correspondence, 2012–2013 (Box 61)
      - Drafts with annotations, correspondence, 2009–2012 (Box 61)
    - Whitman/Williams notes, 1980–1982 (Box 61)
    - Williams, William Carlos, review, undated (Box 61)
    - Writing drafts, 2009–2010 (Box 61)
    - Writing drafts, notes, 2005–2014 (Box 61)
    - Zen anthology, 2004 (Box 61)
  - Artwork
    This subseries includes Heyen's glass bottle poetry, card-sleeve art poems, and a painting for Heyen by DeLoss McGraw.
    - Bottle art poems, 2014 (Box 62)
    - Card-sleeve poetry, 2014 (Box 63)
    - DeLoss for Heyen, 2005 (Box 64)
  - Annotated Books
    This subseries consists of books collected by Heyen that include his annotations and early drafts of his poetry written on flyleaves and in margins.
    - Appelfeld, Aharon. Beyond Despair: Three Lectures and a Conversation with Philip Roth, 1994 (Box 65)
      Annotated.
    - Atwood, Margaret. Negotiating with the Dead: A Writer on Writing, 2002 (Box 65)
      This book contains drafts of about 25 of the 13-syllable poems that will go into The Orphanage: 1313 poems. See back flyleaves.
    - Baker, Nicholson. Double Fold: Libraries and the Assault on Paper, 2001 (Box 65)
      Contains the first draft of the 6-line scherzo Oink (p. 206).
    - Bernstein, Jeremy. Albert Einstein and the Frontiers of Physics, 1996 (Box 65)
      Contains the first drafts of about 30 scherzi.
    - Berr, Helene. Journal, 1988 (Box 65)
      Contains drafts of a half-dozen scherzo and of Helene Berr: Katyn, 1941.
    - Berry, Wendell. Life is a Miracle: An Essay Against Modern Superstition, 2000 (Box 65)
      Contains the first drafts of a couple scherzo.
    - Birkerts, Sven. The Electric Life: Essays on Modern Poetry, 1989 (Box 65)
      Contains drafts of a couple of poems that came to nothing.
    - Blake, Michael. Dances with Wolves, 1991 (Box 65)
      Contains the 1st drafts of a half-dozen scherzi.
    - Braider, Donald. George Bellows and the Ashcan School of Painting, 1971 (Box 65)
      Annotations toward my 2003 Memorial Art Gallery George Bellows: Autumn Brook broadside.
    - Burkett, Charles William. The Farmer's Veterinarian, 1915 (Box 65)
      Contains drafts of many lines for the two longest sections of Chestnut Rain.
    - Burr, Chandler. The Perfect Scent: A Year Behind the Scenes of the Perfume Industry in Paris & New York, 2008 (Box 65)
      This book contains first drafts of 25-30 of the 13-syllable poems that will go into The Orphanage: 1300 Poems.
    - Close, Frank. Too Hot to Handle: The Race for Cold Fusion, 1991 (Box 65)
      Contains a draft of a poem that came to nothing. Back flyleaf. Notes laid in.
    - Coffey, Marilyn. Great Plains Patchwork: A Memoir, 1989 (Box 65)
      Contains the 1st drafts of a couple poems that got into the Crazy Horse & the Custers: The River of Electricity manuscript.
    - Commoner, Barry. Making Peace with the Planet, 1990 (Box 66)
      This book contains the first draft of my poem "Pterodactyl" which appears in The Rope (2003). Notes laid in.
    - Deshusses, Jerome. The Eighth Night of Creation: Life on the Edge of Human History, 1982 (Box 66)
      Contains the first drafts of about 20 scherzi +.
    - Epstein, Daniel Mark. Lincoln and Whitman: Parallel Lives in Civil War Washington, 2004 (Box 66)
      Contains the first drafts of several scherzo & of one longer poem (p. 209).
    - Exley, Frederick. A Fan's Notes, 1968 (Box 66)
      Contains the 1st draft of the poem that became "Bluing Water."
    - Feiler, Bruce. Walking the Bible: A Journey by Land through the Five Books of Moses, 2001 (Box 66)
      Contains the first draft of "Splinter" & the first drafts of several scherzo, etc.
    - Fifty Cent (w. Robert Greene). The 50th Law, 2009 (Box 66)
      This book contains drafts of about a dozen scherzi.
    - Frankfurter, Bernhard. Ed. The Meeting: An Auschwitz Survivor Confronts an SS Physician, 2000 (Box 66)
      Contains the first drafts of 2-3 poems including "The Candle" & "Gypsies" and "Dagmar Ostermann".
    - Gibbons, Robert. Olson/Still: Crossroad, 2013 (Box 66)
      Signed by Gibbons. Contains drafts of several scherzi.